<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>At the rose over against the Gray-hound-tavern in the strand, there is a physitian.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B17299</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99889110</idno>
  <idno type="VID">196231</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240903474</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing A4101A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[240]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R232825</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99889110</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99889110e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B17299)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 196231)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:2[239])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>At the rose over against the Gray-hound-tavern in the strand, there is a physitian.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1675?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>With ornamental border at head.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Physicians --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Advertising --  Medicine --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="advert_for_a_doctor">
            <pb facs="tcp:196231:1"/>
            <head>At the <hi>ROSE</hi> over against the <hi>Gray-Hound-Tavern</hi> in the <hi>Strand,</hi> there is a Physitian.</head>
            <p>WHo has such Transcendent Medicines against that Tormenting and Raigning Disease the <hi>Gout,</hi> that if Recent or in Youth, he certainly Cures it, or if Old or Inveterate, gives Ease in the most Violent pains thereof, and so subdues the Morbisick Humour, that it never returns by the same cause. In the Stone, of both Reins and Bladder, Strangury, and all stopages of Urine, he gives speedy relief.</p>
            <p>The Kings Evil, Leprosie, and the inveterate Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey, when ariv'd at the greatest height of Malignity, he will engage the Cure of, with much Ease and Safety.</p>
            <p>The Collick and Jliack Passion, all Gripings of the Guts, Vapors, Windiness of the Stomach, Fitts of the Mother, proceeding from what cause soever he Cures, giving Ease in all those racking Pains, almost in a Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            <p>All sorts of Feavers, <hi>Quotidian, Tertian</hi> and <hi>Quartaen</hi> Agues, all sorts of Fluxes or Looseness, as Dissentery, or Bloody Flux, <hi>Lientery diarrhea,</hi> Dropsies of all sorts, he engages the Cure of, in a very short time by a Safe and Easie method.</p>
            <p>All the Distempers of the Ears, as Violent Paines, Ulcers, the old or inveterate Deafness, with all other curable Distempers, if God permit.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:196231:2"/>
            <p>HE has also the most Prevailent Remedies, that ever were yet found out, to take away the cause of BARRENNESS, by the use of which several Hundreds have Conceived, and brought forth Children, after all hopes of Issue has been despair'd of for many Years.</p>
            <p>He prevents Miscarriage, and Cures all those grievous Diseases happening to Women with Child; and also Easing all those Acute Tormenting Pains after the Birth; and has (by Gods Assistance) found out such a Remedy, which (if taken Fifteen or Twenty days before the time of Travail) shall so prepare the Body, that their Pain becomes more Easie and Gentle; several Women (to their great comfort) have prov'd the worth of this Medicine, who (in the Birth of their former Children) have very hardly escaped with their Lives, by the Blessing of God, have found by the taking of it, that their Labour was (Compara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tively) Easie and Gentle.</p>
            <p>This I was resolv'd to Publish, nor for any desire of gain, but in Compassion to that Tender Weak Sex great numbers of which loose their Lives for the wan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of such a Preparative.</p>
            <p>My Medicines of this kind are both Safe, Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sant, and Powerful. Working neither by Vomit, nor Stool, or any other sensible Operation, being fitted to the most Tender Constitutions.</p>
            <p>Those that have occasion may find him at the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mention'd Place, where he will furnish them with proper Remedies compos'd by himself only.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>